Osama Shahid . Jarvis Consulting

I have completed my Bachelor's in Chemistry from McMaster University, but always had a keen interest in technology, as I worked as a junior Software Developer afterwards. I am currently finishing up my Master degree in Computer Science andhave alongside have joined Jarvis. Since then, I have been collaborating with my team members in an Agile/Scrum environment. With that, I have acquired and solidified my knowledge by working on multiple projects specifically technologies like Linux/Bash, RDMS/PostgresSQL, Docker, Maven, etc. I am passionate about solving real-world problems and want to move forward in my career as a Software Developer.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Python, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, NoSQL/MongoDB, Agile/Scrum, Git

Competent: JavaScript, React, Nodejs, HTML/CSS, GitFlow

Familiar: Docker, C/C++, Neo4j, Maven, AWS

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis data eng demo OsamaShahid

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Implented a clustering monitoring program which automates the collects hardware and cpu usage information from the linux servers using Bash scripts and Crontab. The data was stored in a postgresSQL database that was initialized using Dockers. It was later than queried to perform analytics on overall usage and identify downtimes during high server usage. We utilized Git as a version control tool and GitFlow branching strategy.

Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Twitter App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.
- JDBC App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.
- Grep App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.

Springboot App [GitHub]: Not Started

Python Data Analytics [GitHub]: Not Started

Hadoop [GitHub]: Not Started
Spark [GitHub]: Not Started

Cloud/DevOps [GitHub]: Not Started

Highlighted Projects

Fifa Dashboard [GitHub]: Created dashboard to find players team and matches played statistics that can potentially be used for sports betting. The frontend application was built using React and backend using Nodejs. The data was stored in MySQL database hosted on AWS-RDS.

Machine Learning: Suspendisse a tincidunt odio. Suspendisse posuere luctus aliquet. Quisque magna tellus, tempor vitae arcu sed, volutpat scelerisque lacus. Aliquam varius pulvinar dapibus. Ut a tincidunt sem. Aenean sollicitudin fringilla erat ut imperdiet. Phasellus fermentum, enim vitae laoreet elementum, eros nisl hendrerit lorem.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (2021-present): Worked in an Agile/Scrum environment to implement multiple projects using Linux/Bash, Java, Docker, SQL, etc. Conducted daily scrum meetings and bi-weekly retro meetings.

Software Developer, Select Vantage Inc. (2019-2020): Created python tools/programs to help retrieve live trading information. Utilized python modules for data processing and data analysis and implemented scripts to reduce time sorting data.

Education

Univeristy of Pennsylvannia (2020-Present), Masters of Computer Information Technology, School of Engineering and Applied Sciences - GPA: 3.7/4.0

McMaster University (2015-2019), Bachelors of Science, Chemistry and Chemical Biology - GPA: 3.5/4.0

Miscellaneous

- Soccer and Basketball
- Competitive gaming
- Photography and Radio Co-Host